[
    {
        "question": "My people are destroyed for lack of knowledge; because you have rejected knowledge, I reject you from being a priest to me. And since you have forgotten the law of your God, I also will forget your children. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:6",
        "rank": "469"
    },
    {
        "question": "When Israel was a child, I loved him, and out of Egypt I called my son. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 11:1",
        "rank": "943"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the LORD first spoke through Hosea, the LORD said to Hosea, \u201cGo, take to yourself a wife of whoredom and have children of whoredom, for the land commits great whoredom by forsaking the LORD.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:2",
        "rank": "1,408"
    },
    {
        "question": "For I desire steadfast love(1) and not sacrifice, the knowledge of God rather than burnt offerings. Footnotes (1) 6:6 Septuagint *mercy* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 6:6",
        "rank": "1,538"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the LORD said to him, \u201cCall his name Jezreel, for in just a little while I will punish the house of Jehu for the blood of Jezreel, and I will put an end to the kingdom of the house of Israel. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:4",
        "rank": "2,036"
    },
    {
        "question": "You shall stumble by day; the prophet also shall stumble with you by night; and I will destroy your mother. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:5",
        "rank": "2,826"
    },
    {
        "question": "lest I strip her naked and make her as in the day she was born, and make her like a wilderness, and make her like a parched land, and kill her with thirst. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:3",
        "rank": "2,901"
    },
    {
        "question": "She conceived again and bore a daughter. And the LORD said to him, \u201cCall her name No Mercy,(1) for I will no more have mercy on the house of Israel, to forgive them at all. Footnotes (1) 1:6 Hebrew *Lo-ruhama*, which means *she has not received mercy* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:6",
        "rank": "2,940"
    },
    {
        "question": "And on that day I will break the bow of Israel in the Valley of Jezreel.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:5",
        "rank": "2,941"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hear the word of the LORD, O children of Israel, for the LORD has a controversy with the inhabitants of the land. There is no faithfulness or steadfast love, and no knowledge of God in the land; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:1",
        "rank": "2,980"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cCome, let us return to the LORD; for he has torn us, that he may heal us; he has struck us down, and he will bind us up. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 6:1",
        "rank": "3,204"
    },
    {
        "question": "But I will have mercy on the house of Judah, and I will save them by the LORD their God. I will not save them by bow or by sword or by war or by horses or by horsemen.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:7",
        "rank": "3,401"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the children of Judah and the children of Israel shall be gathered together, and they shall appoint for themselves one head. And they shall go up from the land, for great shall be the day of Jezreel. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:11",
        "rank": "3,436"
    },
    {
        "question": "When she had weaned No Mercy, she conceived and bore a son. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:8",
        "rank": "3,453"
    },
    {
        "question": "But like Adam they transgressed the covenant; there they dealt faithlessly with me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 6:7",
        "rank": "3,492"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the LORD said, \u201cCall his name Not My People,(1) for you are not my people, and I am not your God.\u201d(2) Footnotes (1) 1:9 Hebrew *Lo-ammi*, which means *not my people* (2) 1:9 Hebrew *I am not yours* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 1:9",
        "rank": "3,529"
    },
    {
        "question": "(1) Ephraim has surrounded me with lies, and the house of Israel with deceit, but Judah still walks with God and is faithful to the Holy One. Footnotes (1) 11:12 Ch 12:1 in Hebrew (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 11:12",
        "rank": "3,723"
    },
    {
        "question": "Like grapes in the wilderness, I found Israel. Like the first fruit on the fig tree in its first season, I saw your fathers. But they came to Baal-peor and consecrated themselves to the thing of shame, and became detestable like the thing they loved. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 9:10",
        "rank": "4,023"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gilead is a city of evildoers, tracked with blood. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 6:8",
        "rank": "4,057"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim mixes himself with the peoples; Ephraim is a cake not turned. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 7:8",
        "rank": "4,235"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon her children also I will have no mercy, because they are children of whoredom. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:4",
        "rank": "4,249"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim was a trained calf that loved to thresh, and I spared her fair neck; but I will put Ephraim to the yoke; Judah must plow; Jacob must harrow for himself. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:11",
        "rank": "4,378"
    },
    {
        "question": "With their flocks and herds they shall go to seek the LORD, but they will not find him; he has withdrawn from them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 5:6",
        "rank": "4,438"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim\u2019s glory shall fly away like a bird\u2014 no birth, no pregnancy, no conception! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 9:11",
        "rank": "4,531"
    },
    {
        "question": "By a prophet the LORD brought Israel up from Egypt, and by a prophet he was guarded. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:13",
        "rank": "4,577"
    },
    {
        "question": "For they have gone up to Assyria, a wild donkey wandering alone; Ephraim has hired lovers. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 8:9",
        "rank": "4,698"
    },
    {
        "question": "The more they increased, the more they sinned against me; I will change their glory into shame. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:7",
        "rank": "4,782"
    },
    {
        "question": "They feed on the sin(1) of my people; they are greedy for their iniquity. Footnotes (1) 4:8 Or *sin offering* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:8",
        "rank": "4,989"
    },
    {
        "question": "For their mother has played the whore; she who conceived them has acted shamefully. For she said, \u2018I will go after my lovers, who give me my bread and my water, my wool and my flax, my oil and my drink.\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:5",
        "rank": "4,990"
    },
    {
        "question": "Though he may flourish among his brothers, the east wind, the wind of the LORD, shall come, rising from the wilderness, and his fountain shall dry up; his spring shall be parched; it shall strip his treasury of every precious thing. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 13:15",
        "rank": "5,078"
    },
    {
        "question": "As robbers lie in wait for a man, so the priests band together; they murder on the way to Shechem; they commit villainy. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 6:9",
        "rank": "5,141"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore I will hedge up her(1) way with thorns, and I will build a wall against her, so that she cannot find her paths. Footnotes (1) 2:6 Hebrew *your* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:6",
        "rank": "5,358"
    },
    {
        "question": "Afterward the children of Israel shall return and seek the LORD their God, and David their king, and they shall come in fear to the LORD and to his goodness in the latter days. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 3:5",
        "rank": "5,362"
    },
    {
        "question": "Strangers devour his strength, and he knows it not; gray hairs are sprinkled upon him, and he knows it not. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 7:9",
        "rank": "5,412"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim has given bitter provocation; so his Lord will leave his bloodguilt on him and will repay him for his disgraceful deeds. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:14",
        "rank": "5,455"
    },
    {
        "question": "They have dealt faithlessly with the LORD; for they have borne alien children. Now the new moon shall devour them with their fields. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 5:7",
        "rank": "5,827"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the house of Israel I have seen a horrible thing; Ephraim\u2019s whoredom is there; Israel is defiled. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 6:10",
        "rank": "5,853"
    },
    {
        "question": "Because Ephraim has multiplied altars for sinning, they have become to him altars for sinning. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 8:11",
        "rank": "5,880"
    },
    {
        "question": "Even if they bring up children, I will bereave them till none is left. Woe to them when I depart from them! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 9:12",
        "rank": "6,041"
    },
    {
        "question": "Though they hire allies among the nations, I will soon gather them up. And the king and princes shall soon writhe because of the tribute. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 8:10",
        "rank": "6,056"
    },
    {
        "question": "And it shall be like people, like priest; I will punish them for their ways and repay them for their deeds. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:9",
        "rank": "6,084"
    },
    {
        "question": "Blow the horn in Gibeah, the trumpet in Ramah. Sound the alarm at Beth-aven; we follow you,(1) O Benjamin! Footnotes (1) 5:8 Or *after you* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 5:8",
        "rank": "6,153"
    },
    {
        "question": "For you also, O Judah, a harvest is appointed. When I restore the fortunes of my people, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 6:11",
        "rank": "6,213"
    },
    {
        "question": "And she did not know that it was I who gave her the grain, the wine, and the oil, and who lavished on her silver and gold, which they used for Baal. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:8",
        "rank": "6,385"
    },
    {
        "question": "whoredom, wine, and new wine, which take away the understanding. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:11",
        "rank": "6,402"
    },
    {
        "question": "They sacrifice on the tops of the mountains and burn offerings on the hills, under oak, poplar, and terebinth, because their shade is good. Therefore your daughters play the whore, and your brides commit adultery. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:13",
        "rank": "6,412"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have plowed iniquity; you have reaped injustice; you have eaten the fruit of lies. Because you have trusted in your own way and in the multitude of your warriors, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:13",
        "rank": "6,561"
    },
    {
        "question": "As they go, I will spread over them my net; I will bring them down like birds of the heavens; I will discipline them according to the report made to their congregation. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 7:12",
        "rank": "6,578"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore I will take back my grain in its time, and my wine in its season, and I will take away my wool and my flax, which were to cover her nakedness. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:9",
        "rank": "6,626"
    },
    {
        "question": "She shall pursue her lovers but not overtake them, and she shall seek them but shall not find them. Then she shall say, \u2018I will go and return to my first husband, for it was better for me then than now.\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:7",
        "rank": "6,652"
    },
    {
        "question": "therefore the tumult of war shall arise among your people, and all your fortresses shall be destroyed, as Shalman destroyed Beth-arbel on the day of battle; mothers were dashed in pieces with their children. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:14",
        "rank": "6,839"
    },
    {
        "question": "A merchant, in whose hands are false balances, he loves to oppress. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:7",
        "rank": "6,920"
    },
    {
        "question": "Every evil of theirs is in Gilgal; there I began to hate them. Because of the wickedness of their deeds I will drive them out of my house. I will love them no more; all their princes are rebels. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 9:15",
        "rank": "6,944"
    },
    {
        "question": "Woe to them, for they have strayed from me! Destruction to them, for they have rebelled against me! I would redeem them, but they speak lies against me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 7:13",
        "rank": "7,157"
    },
    {
        "question": "(1) Say to your brothers, \u201cYou are my people,\u201d(2) and to your sisters, \u201cYou have received mercy.\u201d(3) Footnotes (1) 2:1 Ch 2:3 in Hebrew (2) 2:1 Hebrew *ammi*, which means *my people* (3) 2:1 Hebrew *ruhama*, which means *she has received mercy* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:1",
        "rank": "7,282"
    },
    {
        "question": "They shall eat, but not be satisfied; they shall play the whore, but not multiply, because they have forsaken the LORD to cherish (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:10",
        "rank": "7,306"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus it shall be done to you, O Bethel, because of your great evil. At dawn the king of Israel shall be utterly cut off. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:15",
        "rank": "7,353"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cPlead with your mother, plead\u2014 for she is not my wife, and I am not her husband\u2014 that she put away her whoring from her face, and her adultery from between her breasts; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:2",
        "rank": "7,427"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now I will uncover her lewdness in the sight of her lovers, and no one shall rescue her out of my hand. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:10",
        "rank": "7,483"
    },
    {
        "question": "The inhabitants of Samaria tremble for the calf(1) of Beth-aven. Its people mourn for it, and so do its idolatrous priests\u2014 those who rejoiced over it and over its glory\u2014 for it has departed(2) from them. Footnotes (1) 10:5 Or *calves* (2) 10:5 Or *has gone into exile* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:5",
        "rank": "7,596"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will punish her for the days she burned incense to the Baals; she decked herself with rings and jewelry, and went after her lovers, but me she forgot,\" declares the LORD.\"",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:13",
        "rank": "7,597"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Ephraim is blighted, their root is withered, they yield no fruit. Even if they bear children, I will slay their cherished offspring.\"",
        "answer": "Hosea 9:16",
        "rank": "7,624"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will ruin her vines and her fig trees, which she said were her pay from her lovers; I will make them a thicket, and wild animals will devour them.",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:12",
        "rank": "7,648"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will stop all her celebrations: her yearly festivals, her New Moons, her Sabbath days \u2013 all her appointed festivals.",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:11",
        "rank": "7,649"
    },
    {
        "question": "Israel's arrogance testifies against him, but despite all this he does not return to the LORD his God or search for him.",
        "answer": "Hosea 7:10",
        "rank": "7,672"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Israel has forgotten their Maker and built palaces; Judah has fortified many towns. But I will send fire on their cities that will consume their fortresses.\"",
        "answer": "Hosea 8:14",
        "rank": "7,738"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim will be laid waste on the day of reckoning. Among the tribes of Israel I proclaim what is certain.",
        "answer": "Hosea 5:9",
        "rank": "7,739"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I will not punish your daughters when they turn to prostitution, nor your daughters-in-law when they commit adultery, because the men themselves consort with harlots and sacrifice with shrine prostitutes \u2013  a people without understanding will come to ruin!\"",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:14",
        "rank": "7,787"
    },
    {
        "question": "My God will reject them because they have not obeyed him; they will be wanderers among the nations.",
        "answer": "Hosea 9:17",
        "rank": "7,858"
    },
    {
        "question": "My people consult a wooden idol and are answered by a stick of wood. A spirit of prostitution leads them astray; they are unfaithful to their God.",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:12",
        "rank": "7,859"
    },
    {
        "question": "I wrote for them the many things of my law, but they regarded them as something foreign.",
        "answer": "Hosea 8:12",
        "rank": "7,967"
    },
    {
        "question": "There I will give her back her vineyards, and will make the Valley of Achor a door of hope. There she will respond as in the days of her youth, as in the day she came up out of Egypt.",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:15",
        "rank": "8,147"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I will plant her for myself in the land; I will show my love to the one I called 'Not my loved one.' I will say to those called 'Not my people,' 'You are my people'; and they will say, 'You are my God.\"",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:23",
        "rank": "8,229"
    },
    {
        "question": "Israel was a spreading vine; he brought forth fruit for himself. As his fruit increased, he built more altars; as his land prospered, he adorned his sacred stones.",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:1",
        "rank": "8,262"
    },
    {
        "question": "In that day I will make a covenant for them with the beasts of the field, the birds in the sky and the creatures that move along the ground. Bow and sword and battle I will abolish from the land, so that all may lie down in safety.",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:18",
        "rank": "8,263"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"How can I give you up, Ephraim? How can I hand you over, Israel? How can I treat you like Admah? How can I make you like Zeboyim? My heart is changed within me; all my compassion is aroused.\"",
        "answer": "Hosea 11:8",
        "rank": "8,372"
    },
    {
        "question": "Though you play the whore, O Israel, let not Judah become guilty. Enter not into Gilgal, nor go up to Beth-aven, and swear not, \u201cAs the LORD lives.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:15",
        "rank": "8,439"
    },
    {
        "question": "When their drink is gone, they give themselves to whoring; their rulers(1) dearly love shame. Footnotes (1) 4:18 Hebrew *shields* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:18",
        "rank": "8,505"
    },
    {
        "question": "For now they will say: \u201cWe have no king, for we do not fear the LORD; and a king\u2014what could he do for us?\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:3",
        "rank": "8,530"
    },
    {
        "question": "The princes of Judah have become like those who move the landmark; upon them I will pour out my wrath like water. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 5:10",
        "rank": "8,575"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will not execute my burning anger; I will not again destroy Ephraim; for I am God and not a man, the Holy One in your midst, and I will not come in wrath.(1) Footnotes (1) 11:9 Or *into the city* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 11:9",
        "rank": "8,748"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim feeds on the wind and pursues the east wind all day long; they multiply falsehood and violence; they make a covenant with Assyria, and oil is carried to Egypt. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:1",
        "rank": "8,785"
    },
    {
        "question": "I led them with cords of kindness,(1) with the bands of love, and I became to them as one who eases the yoke on their jaws, and I bent down to them and fed them. Footnotes (1) 11:4 Or *humaneness*; Hebrew *man* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 11:4",
        "rank": "8,786"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will return again to my place, until they acknowledge their guilt and seek my face, and in their distress earnestly seek me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 5:15",
        "rank": "8,819"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cAnd in that day I will answer, declares the LORD, I will answer the heavens, and they shall answer the earth, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:21",
        "rank": "8,973"
    },
    {
        "question": "As for my sacrificial offerings, they sacrifice meat and eat it, but the LORD does not accept them. Now he will remember their iniquity and punish their sins; they shall return to Egypt. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 8:13",
        "rank": "9,107"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim is like a dove, silly and without sense, calling to Egypt, going to Assyria. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 7:11",
        "rank": "9,255"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim is oppressed, crushed in judgment, because he was determined to go after filth.(1) Footnotes (1) 5:11 Or *to follow human precepts* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 5:11",
        "rank": "9,256"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim is joined to idols; leave him alone. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:17",
        "rank": "9,257"
    },
    {
        "question": "For I will remove the names of the Baals from her mouth, and they shall be remembered by name no more. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:17",
        "rank": "9,382"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ephraim, as I have seen, was like a young palm(1) planted in a meadow; but Ephraim must lead his children out to slaughter.(2) Footnotes (1) 9:13 Or *like Tyre* (2) 9:13 Hebrew *to him who slaughters* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 9:13",
        "rank": "9,423"
    },
    {
        "question": "there is swearing, lying, murder, stealing, and committing adultery; they break all bounds, and bloodshed follows bloodshed. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:2",
        "rank": "9,465"
    },
    {
        "question": "He strove with the angel and prevailed; he wept and sought his favor. He met God(1) at Bethel, and there God spoke with us\u2014 Footnotes (1) 12:4 Hebrew *him* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:4",
        "rank": "9,615"
    },
    {
        "question": "I spoke to the prophets; it was I who multiplied visions, and through the prophets gave parables. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:10",
        "rank": "9,722"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high places of Aven, the sin of Israel, shall be destroyed. Thorn and thistle shall grow up on their altars, and they shall say to the mountains, \u201cCover us,\u201d and to the hills, \u201cFall on us.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 10:8",
        "rank": "9,805"
    },
    {
        "question": "They do not cry to me from the heart, but they wail upon their beds; for grain and wine they gash themselves; they rebel against me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 7:14",
        "rank": "9,862"
    },
    {
        "question": "Like a stubborn heifer, Israel is stubborn; can the LORD now feed them like a lamb in a broad pasture? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 4:16",
        "rank": "9,863"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the womb he took his brother by the heel, and in his manhood he strove with God. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:3",
        "rank": "9,969"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will betroth you to me in faithfulness. And you shall know the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 2:20",
        "rank": "9,970"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD has an indictment against Judah and will punish Jacob according to his ways; he will repay him according to his deeds. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Hosea 12:2",
        "rank": "10,207"
    }
]